我的天  泰尔西
Oh, my God, Tyreese!
没事吧
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
我们得继续走
We gotta keep moving.
-其他人呢  -刚还在我身后
- Where's everybody else? - They were just behind me.
前面安全吗
Is there a clearing ahead?
-有没有地方休整  -我没去那么远
- A place to regroup? - I didn't get very far.
前面可能有座建筑
There might be a building up ahead.
我好像在树林中看到塔了
I thought I saw a tower past the trees.
什么样的塔
Tower? What kind of tower?
这边
This way!
快
Come on!
快走  快走
Come on, come on, come on.
妈
Mom!
快
Come on!
快点  这边走
Hurry! This way!
快
Come on!
还不知道里面是否安全
We don't know what's in there.
但外面肯定不安全
We know what's out here.
不能带她
Not her.
别这样
Don't.
她在拖累你  在拖累我们
She's slowing you down, she's slowing us down.
而我们进去后  要是她变行尸了
And once we're in there, when she turns...
她说的对  你得留下我
She's right. You gotta leave me.
不  拜托
No. Please.
它们会把她生吞活剥的
They'll tear her apart.
萨沙
Sasha.
-不能这么做  -你想带着她到处逃命吗
- We can't do this. - You wanna drag her around?
她很痛苦  而当她最后转化...
She's suffering. And when she finally turns--
本还不能失去妈妈
Ben's not ready.
-这绝对是个错误  -也许吧
- It's a mistake. - Maybe.
《行尸走肉》
我答应米尔顿会帮他火化科尔曼先生的尸体
I promised Milton I'd help him cremate Mr. Coleman's body.
你真好
That's sweet of you,
但你要是还不舒服  他可以独自解决
but if you're still rattled, he can handle it himself.
他不用
He shouldn't have to.
你团结起来的这些人
All these people you've brought together,
他们到这来可不仅仅是寻求保护
they're here for more than just protection;
他们在互相支撑共度难关
they're helping each other through this mess.
你开始喜欢上伍德伯里了对吗
Woodbury's starting to grow on you, huh?
很好
Good.
佩妮
Penny?
亲爱的
Honey?
爸爸来了
It's Daddy.
宝贝
Baby.
过来
Come here.
爸爸去打猎
*Daddy's gone a-hunting*
猎回小兔皮
*To get a little rabbit skin*
为宝贝添衣
*To wrap his baby...*
看着我  宝贝
Look at me, baby.
看着我
Look at me.
看我
Look at me!
玛姬  他有没有
Maggie, did he--
没有
No.
他没怎么碰我
He barely touched me.
这么久以来  我们一直逃避行尸
All this time, running from walkers--
却忘了活人的丑恶
you forget what people do,
他们一向如此丑恶
have always done.
看看他们对你下的毒手
Look at what they did to you.
没事的
Doesn't matter.
只要他没有对你...
As long as he didn't--
没有  真的
No. I promise.
该死
Damn it.
好吧  我们得轻装上阵
All right, we need to downsize.
我们不可能搜遍每座建筑
Ain't no way we're gonna check in all them buildings,
守卫太多了
not with all them guards there.
好了  出发
All right, let's go.
监狱是绝佳的藏身之处
The prison's the perfect place to hole up.
以前关囚犯  现在防行尸
What once kept prisoners in now keeps biters out.
这个方法很聪明
And that's smart.
你打算占领那里  把伍德伯里搬过去吗
You thinking of taking it over, moving Woodbury there?
大家喜欢这里  因为这里和以前的生活一样
People love it here because it feels like what was.
让他们住在牢房里  四周都是铁栅栏吗
Move them to damp cells surrounded by barbed wire?
不行
No.
我们把住在监狱的那群人干掉
We gotta take out the group that's living there.
让行尸重新涌入那里  没人会知道发生了什么
Let the biters move back in. No one'll be the wiser.
问题是  我弟弟和他们在一起
The problem is my brother's with them.
你可以和他谈谈
Well, you'll talk to him.
让他做我们的内线
Make him our inside man.
接应我们进去
He'll get us in there.
我们先举白旗示弱
We'll wave the white flag
就像国民警卫队那次一样
like we did with the National Guard.
达里尔不能有事
Nothing happens to Daryl.
当然
Of course not.
格伦和那个姑娘怎么办
What about Glenn and the girl?
他们在这待的时间越长
Well, the longer they're here,
安德莉亚发现真相的可能性就越大
the more chance Andrea will find out.
把他们带到恐怖角
Take them to the Screamer Pits.
这里就是你被关的地方
This is where you were held?
我在这里被审问
I was questioned.
他们还会被关在其他什么地方吗
Any idea where else they could be?
我记得你说过有宵禁
I thought you said there was a curfew.
白天街上都是人  这些人还没回去而已
The street is packed during the day. Those are stragglers.
如果有人进来  我们就无处可躲了
If anyone comes in here, we're sitting ducks.
我们得离开这
We gotta move.
他们可能被关在他公寓里
They could be in his apartment.
是吗  如果不在呢
Yeah? What if they ain't?
那我们就去别的地方找
Then we'll look somewhere else.
你说过你能帮我们
You said you could help us.
我已经尽我所能了
I'm doing what I can.
那他们人在哪儿
Then where in the hell are they?
如果这事黄了  我们就丢下她
If this goes south, we're cutting her loose.
你觉得她在引我们入陷阱吗
You think she's leading us into a trap?
反正现在我们毫无头绪
Right now it's the blind leading the blind.
咱们分开行动吧
Let's split up.
我知道你在这里
I know you're in here.
我在外面看到动静了
I saw you moving from outside.
别装神弄鬼了
All right, now.
你不应该进这儿的  你自己明白
You're not supposed to be in here and you know it.
谁在这儿
Who's in here?
闭嘴  跪下
Shut up. Get on your knees.
手背后
Hands behind your back.
绑紧他
Zip tie him.
我们的人在哪儿
Where are our people?
我不知道  我不知道
I don't know. I don't know.
你们扣了我们的人
You are holding some of our people.
-他们在哪儿  -我不知道
- Where the hell are they? - I don't know.
张嘴
Open your mouth.
你真会哄小孩
You are good with her.
你有妹妹吗
You got little sisters?
没有
No.
-你到底多大了  -十七岁
- How old are you, anyway? - 17.
十七岁  如花少女啊
17. Interesting.
我能和你聊聊吗
May I speak with you?
我吗
Me?
我一会回来
I'll be right back.
-有什么问题  -离她远点
- What's the problem? - Stay away from her.
拜托
Please.
我们来这儿不是为了谈情说爱
This isn't about you trying to repopulate the earth.
我并无冒犯之意
I didn't mean no offense.
我被关起来有一阵儿了
I've been locked up a long while
这里连女人的影子都没有
and, well, there weren't many women.
你明白吗
You follow me?
玛姬和格伦是一对  你又是同性恋
I mean, Maggie, she's with Glenn and you're a lesbian.
我只能和她聊天
I was just talking with her.
我不是同性恋
I'm not a lesbian.
你留着  短发
You got the... short hair.
你不是同性恋
You're not a lesbian?
哎呦
My, my,
如花大婶啊
this is interesting.
别打歪主意了
No, it's not.
放开他
Let him go!
好的
OK.
把枪给我
Give me the gun!
站起来
Get up!
能叙叙旧真不错
Glad we could catch up.
看着我
Just keep looking at me.
我爱你
I love you.
站起来  走  快走  快
On your feet, move. Let's go, come on.
见鬼
Shit.
怎么回事  妈的
What the hell? Aw, shit!
枪声从那边传来
Shots came from up there.
-我去看看  -不  我来处理
- I'm gonna check it out. - No, I'll handle it.
有时行尸会突破边防栅栏
Sometimes biters get in through the side fence.
不需要恐慌
There's no need for anyone to panic.
快来人啊
Someone help!
怎么了
What happened?
有人持枪闯了进来
Guys came through with guns.
多少人
How many?
我...  我不知道
I-- I don't know.
好吧  仔细想想
Well, think.
六七个人吧  从来没见过他们
Six or seven guys. I've never seen them.
我们遭袭击了吗  要怎么办
Are we under attack? What should we do?
所有人请回到屋子里  关好门
Everyone, please just go home, lock your doors, huh?
我们需要确保大家的安全
We need to keep everyone safe, okay?
所以现在马上进屋  把灯关掉
So just get inside, keep your lights off.
快点
Come on.
我们遭到了袭击
We're under attack.
你们去地毯式搜索那几个人
You fan out and you find these people.
不要冒险活捉他们
Don't take any chances, try and take prisoners.
格杀勿论  快点
You shoot to kill, huh? Come on.
进去  快
Inside, quick!
后面无路可走
Ain't no way out back here.
瑞克  你怎么找到我们的
Rick, how did you find us?
伤有多重
How bad are you hurt?
我没事
I'll be all right.
那个女人在哪儿
Where's that woman?
她刚刚就跟在我们后面
She was right behind us.
也许她被抓住了  要我去找她吗
Maybe she was spotted. Want me to go look for her?
不  我们得先带他们离开这儿
No. We gotta get them out of here.
她得靠自己了
She's on her own.
达里尔
Daryl,
这是莫尔干的
this was Merle.
真的  是他
It was. He did this.
-你看到他了  -面对面
- You saw him? - Face to face.
他把行尸推向我  他准备杀我们
Threw a walker at me. He was gonna execute us.
我哥哥就是总督吗
S-So my brother's this governor?
不  总督另有其人
No, it's somebody else.
你哥是他的副官什么的
Your brother's his lieutenant or something.
他知道我和你们在一起吗
Does he know I'm still with you?
现在知道了  瑞克  对不起
He does now. Rick, I'm sorry.
我们告诉他监狱在哪了
We told him where the prison was.
我们实在挺不住了
We couldn't hold out.
没事  不需要道歉
Don't. No need to apologize.
他们会继续搜捕我们
They're gonna be looking for us.
我们得马上回去  你能走吗
We have to get back. Can you walk?
我们的车停在几英里以外
We got a car a few miles out.
-我没事  -好吧
- I'm good. - All right.
如果莫尔在这附近  我得去见见他
Hey, if Merle's around, I need to see him.
现在不行  我们还处在敌营
Not now. We're in hostile territory.
-他是我哥哥  我不能..  -看他干的好事
- He's my brother. I ain't-- - Look at what he did!
听着  我们得马上离开这儿
Look, we gotta-- we gotta get out of here now.
我可以找他谈谈  或许可以解决这件事
Maybe I can talk to him. Maybe I can work something out.
不不不  你现在头脑不清楚
No, no, no. You're not thinking straight.
先别管其他的  他们有伤在身
Look, no matter what they say, they're hurt.
格伦几乎不能走路
Glenn can barely walk.
万一被行尸包围
How are we gonna make it out
又被总督追上
if we get overrun by walkers
我们怎么办
and this governor catches up to us?
我需要你
I need you.
你会帮我吗
Are you with me?
会
Yeah.
-找到他们了吗  -找到谁
- Any sign of them? - Signs of what?
外面究竟什么情况
What exactly is happening out there?
有群混蛋想抢我们的地盘
Some assholes want what we have.
那我们还在这儿干等什么
Then what are we doing waiting around here?
说得对
Damn straight.
我们去干掉这群兔崽子
Let's take these sons of bitches out.
你确定我们的防线被突破了吗
How do we know that the perimeter was breached?
有谁看见他们了
Did anyone actually see them?
-他们杀了沃伦  -沃伦死了
- They killed Warren. - Killed?
近距离袭击  喉咙被戳穿
Got up close, stuck a stake through his neck.
我们要加强巡逻
We need patrols now.
不能给恐怖份子留任何机会
Can't take chances with these terrorists.
你去查看一下居民们  确保他们的安全
You check on our people, make sure they're safe.
你以为我是居委会吗
You want me to do house calls,
挨家挨户查水表吗
make sure everyone's tucked in?
这些家伙可能藏在某户人家中
These guys could be holed up in one of our residences.
也可能挟持居民当人质
They could be holding someone captive or worse.
你找不到其它人干这活了吗
Can't anyone else handle that?
我的经验可以用在其他方面...
I've got a hell of a lot of experience and--
谢谢
Thank you.
大家分散搜查吧
The rest of you split up.
莫尔负责指挥搜查
Merle will lead the search.
干嘛不让海莉去挨家挨户查看
Don't you think Haley should handle the door-to-doors?
我需要一个成年人去安抚人心
I need someone with some authority to provide reassurance.
海莉只是个孩子
I mean, she's just a kid.
这伙人已经杀了一个人  打倒另一个
These people have already killed one man, beaten another.
-我枪法不错  -就照我说的做
- I'm good with a gun-- - Just do as I ask.
好吧
Sure.
我数到三  跟紧点
On three. Stay tight.
一  二  三
One, two, three.
走
Let's go!
当心后面
Behind you!
走  找掩护
Go! Get cover!
去那边
Get there.
走  走
Go, go, go!
你还好吧
You all right?
我看到他们了
I saw them.
-有多少人  -没看清楚
- How many? - I didn't see.
无所谓  反正会越来越多
Don't matter. There's gonna be more of them.
要赶紧转移
We need to move.
至少看见其中一个  黑人  很年轻
One of them, at least. Black guy, young.
好像穿着囚服
Looked like he was wearing a prison jumpsuit.
越狱的犯人
Escaped convicts.
-还有手雷吗  -有
- Any grenades left? - Uh-huh.
准备好手雷  我们必须冲到墙那边
Get them ready. We gotta gun into the wall.
我们得赶紧离开街道
We gotta get off the street.
我们不用拼命  安全第一
We're not soldiers, we're survivors.
把风头避过去吧
We'll wait them out.
烟雾一散去就能...
Once the smoke clears--
不  那时他们早跑了
Nah, they could be anywhere.
离开街道
You get off the street.
你去哪
Where are you going?
-离开街道  快  -妈的
- Off the street. Come on, move! - Oh shit.
你们赶紧走  我来掩护
You guys go ahead. I'm gonna lay down some cover fire.
不行  我们要一起行动
No, we gotta stay together.
太危险了  我会紧跟在你们身后的
Too hairy. I'll be right behind you.
准备好
Ready?
-走  -我们离开这儿
- Move! - Let's get out of here!
-安全  走  -继续走
- Clear! Go!  - Keep going!
这边走
This way!
不
No!
瑞克  瑞克
Rick! Rick!
玛姬
Maggie!
瑞克
Rick!
来啊
Come on!
达里尔
Daryl!
快走
Go!
总算把朱迪思哄睡了
Finally got Judith to sleep.
奶粉还有多少
How are we with formula?
应该还能再撑一个月
We have enough to last us another month.
这周末我和卡萝尔再去弄点儿
I'll take Carol for some more at the end of the week.
那时你爸爸和其他人就回来了
Your dad and the others will be back by then.
这可说不准
We don't know that.
现在  朱迪思是我唯一的亲人
Right now, Judith is the only family I got.
那是什么声音
What was that?
-是监狱里面传来的  -是卡萝尔吗
- That was from inside. - Was that Carol?
她和阿克塞尔去外面哨塔放哨了
She's out keeping watch in the guard tower with Axel.
万一他们有事儿回来了呢
What if they came back in for something?
万一他们有麻烦了呢
What if they're in trouble?
去哨塔看看她是不是在那
Let's check the tower, see if she's there.
怎么还有人可以进得来
How could anyone else get in?
坟墓那儿已经行尸密布了
The tombs are filled with walkers
都是从外面游荡来的
that wandered in from outside.
或许有幸存者也会进来
Someone else could have done the same thing.
我去看看
I'm going.
我不能让你去那边
I can't let you go down there.
换我父亲就会去
My father would go.
不  不要
No, no, no, no!
来啊
Come on!
快点儿
Hurry!
-走  快走  -让我背着吧
-Go! Just go. - Let me take her.
我来掩护你
I'll cover you.
当心
Look out!
-你们不能带上她  -不行
- You have to leave her! - No way!
我的天啊
Oh my God.
没事的
It's okay.
我不会伤害你的
I'm not gonna hurt you.
来啊  来啊  好了
Come on, come on. That's it.
来吧
Come on.
不要
No!
不要伤害她
Don't hurt her.
看我
Look. Hey.
你是冲我来的
It's me you want.
没必要让她承受痛苦
There's no need for her to suffer.
她什么都感觉不到了
She doesn't have needs.
求你了
Please.
不要伤害我女儿
Don't hurt my little girl.
求你了
Please don't.
不
No!
你都做了什么
What have you done?
哦  天哪  我的天
Oh, good God. Oh, my God.
到这儿来
Here, here.
天呐  堂娜
Oh, God! Donna?
她死了吗
Is she dead?
交给我吧
I'll take care of it.
孩子  慢着
Kid. Wait a minute.
-她很快就要变了  -你到底是谁
- She doesn't have that long. - Who the hell are you?
你怎么进来的  还有别人吗
How did you get in here? Who are you with?
听着  我们会帮你们
Look, we can help you.
先办正事
First things first.
不用  我们自己解决吧
No, we take care of our own.
-不要  泰尔西  -必须这么做
- No, Tyreese! - I gotta do it.
听着  带着本去那边墙上背过身
Look, just take Ben and lean against the wall.
就一眨眼的功夫
It'll be quick.
没事的  没事的
It's okay. It's okay.
你要干什么
Hey, what are you doing?
孩子  你打算把我们关在这里吗
Kid, did you just lock us in here?
把门打开
Open the door.
这屋子很安全  你们不会有事的
This room is secure. You'll be safe.
会给你们食物和水
You have food and water.
-把门打开  -我不能
- Open this door. - I can't.
别这样  小兄弟  我们又不是动物
Come on, man. We're not animals.
别这么做
Don't do this.
你不能就这样把我们扔在这里
You can't just leave us in here!
打开门  赶紧给我打开
Open this door! Open it! Now!
萨沙
Sasha!
给我离门远点  别纠缠他了
Back away from their door and let the man go.
看看周围
Look around you.
几周以来最好的条件了
This is the best we've had it in weeks.
人家的地盘
His house.
况且我们还有其他事要处理
We got other things to do.
我们不是来找麻烦的
We don't want any trouble.
-不应该帮帮他们吗  -我帮了
- Shouldn't we help them? - I did.
看上去不妙
It doesn't look good.
被玻璃伤的很重
The glass has done a lot of damage.
我得离开这里
I need to get out of here.
-现在不行  -滚开
- Not yet. - Get out of my way!
能让我们单独说句话吗
Can you give us a minute?
刚怎么回事
What the hell was that?
为什么她会在这里
Why was she here?
你怎么就跟她打起来了
Why were you fighting her?
她是回来杀我的
She came back to kill me.
-为什么  -我还想问你呢
- Why? - You tell me.
你了解她
You knew her.
那些鱼缸  人头
The fish tanks, the heads?
我逼自己看着他们
I made myself look at them.
时刻提示着我外面世界的险恶
Prepared me for the horrors outside.
那佩妮呢
And Penny?
我的天呐
Oh, my God.
我刚刚听说  你还好吗
I just heard. Are you all right?
你的眼睛  是不是...
Your eye, is it...
发生了什么
What happened to you?
我被袭击了
I was attacked.
他们翻墙跑了
They made it over the wall.
明天一早我就去追他们
I'll go after them in the morning.
趴下
Get down.
快点  达里尔
Come on, Daryl.
你跑到哪儿去了
Where the hell were you?
举起手来
Put your hands up.
转过去  转过去
Turn around. Turn around.
找到你想要的东西了吗
Get what you came for?
其他人都哪儿去了
Where are the rest of your people?
奥斯卡被杀了
They got Oscar.
达里尔不见了  你看见他了吗
Daryl is missing. You didn't see him?
要是他有个三长两短  我就...
If anything happens to him, I'll--
是我帮你们救出了他们
I brought you here to save them.
感谢你的帮助
Thanks for the help.
你需要帮手  不论你想把他俩带回监狱
You'll need help to get them back to the prison
还是回去救达里尔
or to go back in there for Daryl.
无论如何  你们都需要我
Either way, you need me.
说什么好呢
What can I say?
自从围墙建好后
Hasn't been a night like this
今晚这样的场面还是头一遭
since the walls were completed.
我本以为噩梦都已过去
And I thought we were past it--
遥想灾情爆发初期
past the days when we all sat,
我们围坐在电视机前
huddled, scared in front of the TV
惊恐万分  惶惶不得终日
during the early days of the outbreak.
那时的恐惧感
The fear we all felt then,
今晚又袭上心头
we felt it again tonight.
我让你们失望了
I failed you.
我曾答应保障大家的安全
I promised to keep you safe.
如今瞅瞅我
Hell, look at me.
知道吗
You know, I--
我本该安慰你们说  会没事的
I should tell you that we'll be okay,
我们很安全
that we're safe,
明早把尸体一埋  然后继续生活
that tomorrow we'll bury our dead and endure,
但我不想这样
but I-- I won't,
我说不出口
because I can't.
因为我也害怕
Because I'm afraid.
没错
That's right.
我害怕恐怖分子会夺走我们的一切
I'm afraid of terrorists who want what we have.
想要摧毁我们
Want to destroy us!
或者更糟...
And worse...
因为其中一名恐怖分子...
because one of those terrorists...
就在我们当中
is one of our own.
莫尔...
Merle...
我的得力助手
the man I counted on,
信赖的伙伴
the man I trusted.
出卖了我们
He led 'em here.
是他放他们进来的
And he let 'em in.
是你
It was you.
谎话连篇
You lied,
出卖了大家
betrayed us all.
这名恐怖分子
This is one of the terrorists.
是莫尔的亲兄弟
Merle's own brother.
大家说我们该怎么处置他们
So what should we do with them, huh?
-杀了他们  -什么
- Kill them! - What?
-该怎么办  -杀了他们
- What you want? -  Kill them!
杀了他们
Kill them!
你不是想找你弟弟吗
You wanted your brother.
现在满意了吧
Now you got him.